<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashna Ahmad</title>
    <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ashna Ahmad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://ashnaahmad.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chilean Telexes and the Allocation Problem</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/writing/chilean_telexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/writing/chilean_telexes/</guid>
      <description>Or, &amp;ldquo;How to Get Britain Moving Again.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Written for the TxP Progress Prize., an essay contest in partnership with Civic Future and New Statesman Spotlight. In the spirit of the competition, I&amp;rsquo;ve explored a solution to resource allocation which goes against my economic instincts, but which has at its core a capable state apparatus that harnesses and democratises cutting-edge technology. I agree entirely with TxP that the apparent depth and entrenchment of certain societal problems do not make a solution any less viable - as long as we fully exploit the possibilities afforded to us by science and technology, and don&amp;rsquo;t wallow in despair!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>Contact LinkedIn Calendly Professional/Academic CV My undergraduate thesis My linguistics notes from Cambridge (repo) Other internet homes Varsity newspaper column Theatre portfolio Weekly Worker newspaper column (N.B. I was 14 when I wrote this column, and my political stances have evolved considerably since!) Prehistoric blog </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On being a failed dropout founder</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/writing/dropout_founder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/writing/dropout_founder/</guid>
      <description>The dropout founder, while representing just 4% of unicorn founders, occupies an outsize place in the popular imagination. Their appeal is not unlike that of an action hero: they have outrageous levels of conviction and self-belief, but also a youthful earnestness and an obsession with impact that means you can&amp;rsquo;t help but root for them. There is some sense that the mere act of straying so far from established paths, at the age where they arguably exert the strongest pull, merits recompense; that anyone with the strength of character to do this is bound to be successful eventually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slavophilia and Socialist Realism</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/writing/slavophilia_socialist_realism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/writing/slavophilia_socialist_realism/</guid>
      <description>Written in 2019, in my past life as an aspiring modern languages degree candidate.&#xA;While much of Europe spent the 19th century reshaping its systems of political and economic organisation, an intense intellectual debate in Russia was redefining the very nature of Russian-ness. The legacy of rulers like Peter I and Catherine I, who were responsible for modernising Russia’s courts, overhauling its army and dramatically increasing its foreign influence and artistic prowess, was deeply divisive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start here</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/start_here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/start_here/</guid>
      <description>TLDR Hi! I'm Ashna, a 24y/o founding engineer and the first employee at a Stockholm-based stealth fintech. Before this, I worked in venture capital for 2 years. I also studied computational cognitive science, interned in B2B sales, software engineering and product management, and had a crack at building my own startup. I like to code, write, meet new people, and understand how others think.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
