<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashna Ahmad</title>
    <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ashna Ahmad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ashnaahmad.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>TLDR Hi! I’m Ashna, a 21 y/o hailing from London and working in Paris. I studied computational cognitive science, interned in B2B sales, software engineering and product management roles, and am now building my own startup as part of the 10th Entrepreneur First Paris cohort. I’m currently building in EdTech, but am more generally motivated by empowering individuals to make creative, informed and impactful decisions.
I’m always up for a chat on Discord (chiapuddingg), LinkedIn, or email if you’re old school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/bilingual_language_processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/bilingual_language_processing/</guid>
      <description>Originally written in 2020. More like a lit review.
In the domains of both lexical and syntactic processing, L2 speakers’ potential for ‘native-like’ processing is a question of whether or not L2 speakers are able to acquire connections between lexical units/grammatical structures and concepts which have the same strength as those which characterise native language processing. A related question is whether processing units for all of a multilingual person’s languages exist within a common structure, within which, at least during initial stages of the process, all languages are coactivated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>Contact LinkedIn Calendly Professional/Academic English CV French CV My undergraduate thesis My linguistics notes from Cambridge (repo) Other internet homes Varsity newspaper column Theatre portfolio Weekly Worker newspaper column (N.B. I was 14 when I wrote this column, and my political stances have evolved considerably since!) Prehistoric blog </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marxism - a Modern Utopia?</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/marxism_utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/marxism_utopia/</guid>
      <description>Originally written for the H.G. Wells Society newsletter in 2016 (when I was 14 and did not know how to reference properly)
1905 was an incredibly exciting time to be contemplating the future. The 19th century had been a century of immense change, and as it drew to a close, a number of emergent ideas about humanity had to be integrated into the “intellectual landscape” of the world. A Modern Utopia was from the outset an attempt to conceptualise a utopia compatible with the post-Enlightenment, post-Industrial Revolution mode of thought: one compatible with the “modern dreamer” and the age after “Darwin quickened the thought of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Dynamics and Sexuality</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/power_dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/power_dynamics/</guid>
      <description>An essay originally written for an exam in 2018, on Lolita and The Bloody Chamber. For an exam essay, I am unreasonably proud of this one. (Apparently it also marks my discovery of MLA?)
“In a good short story”, wrote Greg Hollingshead in 1999, “the meaning is not so abstractable, so portable, as it must be in a novel, but is rather more tightly and ineffably embodied in the formal details of the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slavophilia and Socialist Realism</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/slavophilia_socialist_realism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/slavophilia_socialist_realism/</guid>
      <description>Written in 2019.
While much of Europe spent the 19th century reshaping its systems of political and economic organisation, an intense intellectual debate in Russia was redefining the very nature of Russian-ness. The legacy of rulers like Peter I and Catherine I, who were responsible for modernising Russia’s courts, overhauling its army and dramatically increasing its foreign influence and artistic prowess, was deeply divisive. Although both of these rulers presided over usually popular developments – most notably military victory during the Great Northern War and Russo-Turkish wars – some of the most striking examples of their repressive leadership were their responses to those who challenged their progressive agenda, including the suppression of the Streltsy Rebellion1 and of around 160 popular uprisings between 1762 and 1772.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Other Russian Revolution</title>
      <link>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/other_russian_revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashnaahmad.github.io/essays/other_russian_revolution/</guid>
      <description>Written - as you can probably guess - in 2017.
This year, all eyes are on Russia. It is rather fitting that, as the year of the centenaries of its two most famous revolutions began, the country was all over the news once again, this time for allegedly interfering in the American presidential election. As talks concerning the situation in the Middle East continue and the conflict in Ukraine rages on, not to mention the unfolding of Trump’s presidency and the effect of his drastically different outlook on Russia, 2017 may even rival its century-earlier counterpart in terms of its significance for Russia and the rest of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
